YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 4. National Conventions and Conferences
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. CONVENTION
  - Conventions
    - 12th, 5-11 May 1932 (Minneapolis, Minnesota)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 273, Folder 9)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 273, Folder 10)
      - Assemblies (Box 273, Folder 11)
    - 13th, 2-8 May 1934 (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania)
      - Planning (Box 274, Folder 1)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 274, Folder 2)
        - Reports and recommendations to (Box 274, Folder 3)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 274, Folder 4)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 274, Folder 5)
      - Assemblies (Box 274, Folder 6)
      - Post-convention materials - Reports from convention committees and evaluations (Box 274, Folder 7)
    - 14th, 29 Apr-5 May 1936 (Colorado Springs, Colorado)
      - Planning (Box 274, Folder 8)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - Bulletins and Who's Who on the Ballot? (Box 274, Folder 9)
        - Reports and recommendations to (Box 274, Folder 10)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 275, Folder 1)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 275, Folder 2)
      - Post-convention materials - Reports and Evaluations (Box 275, Folder 3)
    - 15th, 22-28 Apr 1938 (Columbus, Ohio)
      - Planning (Box 275, Folder 4)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 275, Folder 5)
        - Reports and recommendations to (Box 275, Folder 6)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 275, Folder 7)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 275, Folder 8)
      - National Industrial Assembly (Box 275, Folder 9)
      - Post-Convention Committee and staff reports (Box 275, Folder 10-11)
    - 16th, 10-16 Apr 1940 (Atlantic City, New Jersey)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 276, Folder 1)
        - Reports and recommendations to (Box 276, Folder 2)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 276, Folder 3-4)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 276, Folder 5)
      - Assemblies
        - Business and Professional (Box 276, Folder 6)
        - Industrial (Box 276, Folder 7)
        - Student (Box 276, Folder 8)
    - Cancelled convention (Grand Rapids), 1945
      - Convention Committee (Box 277, Folder 1)
      - Pre-Convention materials (Box 277, Folder 2)
      - Election-by-mail material (Box 277, Folder 3)
      - Nation-Wide Discussion materials (Box 277, Folder 4)
    - 17th, 2-8 Mar 1946 (Atlantic City, New Jersey)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 277, Folder 5)
        - Recommendations and Work Book (Box 277, Folder 6)
        - Interracial Charter preparations (Box 277, Folder 7)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 277, Folder 8)
      - Sample convention packet (Box 277, Folder 9)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 277, Folder 10)
      - Post-convention materials (Box 277, Folder 11)
    - 18th, 7-14 Mar 1949 (San Francisco, California)
      - Planning (Box 277, Folder 12)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 277, Folder 13)
        - Work Book (Box 277, Folder 14)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 278, Folder 1-2)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 278, Folder 3)
    - 19th, 1-7 May 1952 (Chicago, Illinois)
      - Planning (Box 278, Folder 4)
      - Pre-convention materials (Box 278, Folder 5)
      - Sample Convention Delegate's Kit (Box 278, Folder 6)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 278, Folder 7)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 278, Folder 8)
      - Assemblies (Box 278, Folder 9)
    - Interim "Neighborhood" Meetings, 1953 (Box 279, Folder 1)
    - 20th, 21-27 Apr 1955 (New York City)
      - Planning (Box 279, Folder 2)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 279, Folder 3)
        - Reports and Recommendations/Work Book (Box 279, Folder 4)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 279, Folder 5)
      - Discussion Groups (Box 279, Folder 6)
      - News clippings and press releases (Box 279, Folder 7)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 279, Folder 8-9)
      - Post Convention Evaluations (Box 279, Folder 10)
      - Convention Committee Final Report (Box 279, Folder 11-12)
    - 21st, 13-19 Mar 1958 (St. Louis, Missouri)
      - Planning Committee (Box 279, Folder 13)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 279, Folder 14)
        - Reports and Recommendations/Work Book (Box 280, Folder 1)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 280, Folder 2-3)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 280, Folder 4)
      - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 280, Folder 5)
      - Post Convention Reports and Evaluations (Box 280, Folder 6)
    - Interim "Neighborhood" Meetings, 1958-59 (Box 280, Folder 7)
    - 22nd, 8-13 May 1961 (Denver, Colorado)
      - Planning (Box 280, Folder 8)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 280, Folder 9)
        - Work Book and Reports (Box 280, Folder 10)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 280, Folder 11)
        - Speeches and reports (Box 281, Folder 1)
      - Typed proceedings - Stenotype Report (Box 281, Folder 2-5)
      - Actions (Box 281, Folder 6)
      - Post-convention materials (Box 281, Folder 7)
    - Interim Leadership Development Meetings/Consultations, 1962-63 (Box 281, Folder 8)
    - 23rd, 20-25 Apr 1964 (Cleveland, Ohio) "Match Us To This Hour"
      - Planning (Box 281, Folder 9)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 281, Folder 10)
        - Work Book (Box 281, Folder 11)
      - Program and other convention materials (Box 282, Folder 1-2)
      - Typed proceedings (Box 282, Folder 3-8)
      - Printed proceedings (Box 283, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 283, Folder 2)
    - 24th, 24-29 Apr 1967 (Boston, Massachusetts)
      - Planning (Box 283, Folder 3)
      - Pre-convention materials (Box 283)
        - General (Box 283, Folder 4)
        - Work Book (Box 283, Folder 5)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 283, Folder 6)
        - Speeches (Box 283, Folder 7)
      - Typed proceedings
        - pp. 1-375 (Box 283, Folder 8-10)
        - pp. 376-897 (Box 284, Folder 1-3)
      - Printed proceedings "Report" (Box 284, Folder 4)
      - National Student Assembly (Box 284, Folder 5)
      - Newspaper clippings and press releases (Box 284, Folder 6)
      - Post Convention Materials (Box 284, Folder 7)
    - 25th, 13-18 Apr 1970 (Houston, Texas) "One Imperative for All"
      - Planning
        - General (Box 284, Folder 8)
        - Minutes and Reports (Box 284, Folder 9)
        - Consideration of moving convention from Houston (Box 284, Folder 10)
        - Protest demonstrations, general (Box 284, Folder 11)
        - End War-Build Peace Moratorium Day (Box 285, Folder 1)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 285, Folder 2)
        - Reports and recommendations to Convention (Box 285, Folder 3)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 285, Folder 4-5)
        - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 285, Folder 6-7)
        - Assemblies: Young Adult and Student (Box 285, Folder 8)
        - National Conference of Black Women in the YWCA (Box 285, Folder 9)
      - Press releases (Box 285, Folder 10)
      - News clippings (Box 285, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence after Convention (Box 285, Folder 12)
    - 26th, 26-31 Mar 1973 (San Diego, California) "The Power and the Glory is in We"
      - Planning (Box 286, Folder 1-2)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 286, Folder 3)
        - Who's Who and Work Book (Box 286, Folder 4)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 286, Folder 5)
        - "Cluster Communities" [small groups] (Box 286, Folder 6)
        - Hearings (Box 286, Folder 7)
        - Election
          - General (Box 286, Folder 8)
          - Master Tally [saved as sample] (Box 286, Folder 9-11)
        - Typed unedited proceedings
          - Mon-Tues (Box 286, Folder 12-13)
          - Wed-Sat (Box 287, Folder 1-10)
        - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 287, Folder 11)
        - Resolutions and Actions (Box 287, Folder 12)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 287, Folder 13)
    - 27th, 21-26 Jun 1976 (South Bend, Indiana) "Freedom to be... Power to Move"
      - Planning
        - General (Box 288, Folder 1)
        - Convention Committee meeting, 19-21 Jan 1975 (Box 288, Folder 2-4)
        - Ad-hoc Committee to Study the Resolutions Process
          - Working Papers (Box 288, Folder 5-6)
          - Amendments and Resolutions (Box 288, Folder 7)
          - Pluralistic Convention delegations (Box 288, Folder 8)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 288, Folder 9)
        - Information Bulletins (Box 288, Folder 10)
        - Working Papers (Box 288, Folder 11)
        - Who's Who and Work Book (Box 288, Folder 12)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 289, Folder 1)
        - Assemblies: Teen, Student, Young Women Committed to Action (Box 289, Folder 2)
        - Hearings (Box 289, Folder 3)
        - Impact Groups [small group meetings] (Box 289, Folder 4)
        - Racial/Ethnic and Age Diversity in the YWCA (Box 289, Folder 5)
        - Resolutions and Amendments (Box 289, Folder 6)
        - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 289, Folder 7)
        - Newspaper clippings (Box 289, Folder 8)
      - Evaluation (Box 289, Folder 9)
    - 28th, 17-22 May 1979 (Dallas, Texas)
      - Planning (Box 289)
        - General (Box 289, Folder 10)
        - Location and ERA (Box 289, Folder 11)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 289, Folder 12)
        - Who's Who and Work Book (Box 289, Folder 13)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 290, Folder 1)
        - Assemblies, Teen and Student (Box 290, Folder 2)
        - Reports and speeches (Box 290, Folder 3)
        - Printed proceedings and actions (Box 290, Folder 4)
        - News clippings and press releases (Box 290, Folder 5)
      - Evaluations and Reactions (Box 290, Folder 6)
      - Post-Convention materials (Box 290, Folder 7)
    - 29th, 3-7 Jun 1982 (Washington, DC)
      - Interim Meetings
        - Goal Group Coordinating Committee, 1981 (Box 290, Folder 8)
        - Goal Groups
          - Financial, 1979-81 (Box 290, Folder 9)
          - Leadership Development, 1979-82 (Box 290, Folder 10)
          - Membership, 1979-80 (Box 290, Folder 11)
          - Program, 1979-82 (Box 290, Folder 12)
          - Public Relations, 1979-81 (Box 290, Folder 13)
        - Implementing Committees, 1979-80 (Box 290, Folder 14-15)
        - "Year One" Meetings, 1979-80, n.d. (Box 291, Folder 1-3)
        - Area Meetings, 1981 (Box 291, Folder 4)
        - Executive Directors' Work Session, Jun 1981 (Box 291, Folder 5)
      - Planning
        - General (Box 291, Folder 6)
        - Commercial Exhibits (Box 291, Folder 7)
      - Pre-convention materials
        - General (Box 291, Folder 8)
        - Who's Who and Work Book (Box 291, Folder 9)
        - "Information Bulletin" (Box 291, Folder 10)
      - "Making a Difference in Public Policy: A Pre-Convention Public Policy Event," 2-3 Jun 1982 (Box 291, Folder 11)
      - Program and other convention materials
        - General (Box 292, Folder 1)
        - Assemblies: Teen and Student (Box 292, Folder 2)
        - Resolutions and Amendments
          - General (Box 292, Folder 3)
          - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 292, Folder 4)
        - Reports to (Box 292, Folder 5)
        - Highlights (Box 292, Folder 6)
        - Verbatim Convention Transcript (Box 292, Folder 7)
      - Press releases, news clippings, and post-convention materials (Box 292, Folder 8)
    - 30th, 21-25 Mar 1985 (San Jose, California) "Women Empowered, a Force for the Future"
      - Cycle and Convention Preparation Meetings, 1983-84 (Box 292, Folder 9)
      - Planning (Box 292, Folder 10)
      - Pre-Convention Global Awareness Event (Box 292, Folder 11)
    - Pre-convention materials
      - General (Box 293, Folder 1)
      - Who's Who and Work Book (Box 293, Folder 2)
    - Convention Materials
      - General (Box 293, Folder 3-4)
      - Assemblies, Teen and Student (Box 293, Folder 5)
      - Resolutions and Amendments (Box 293, Folder 6)
      - Reports to (Box 293, Folder 7)
    - Actions (Box 293, Folder 8)
    - Press releases and news clippings (Box 293, Folder 9)
    - Evaluations and reports (Box 293, Folder 10-11)
  - 31st, 22-26 Jun 1988 (Chicago, Illinois)
    - Convention Preparation Meetings, 1986-88 (Box 293, Folder 12-13)
    - Planning, 1983-88 (Box 294, Folder 1-4)
    - Resolutions Committee
      - General (Box 294, Folder 5)
      - Proposed Amendments (Box 294, Folder 6)
      - Proposed Resolutions (Box 294, Folder 7-8)
    - Pre-Convention materials
      - General (Box 294, Folder 9)
      - Who's Who and Action Agenda (Box 294, Folder 10)
    - Convention materials
      - General (Box 295, Folder 1-2)
      - Assemblies, Teen and Student (Box 295, Folder 3)
      - New YWCA logo launch (Box 295, Folder 4)
      - Reports to (Box 295, Folder 5)
      - Resolutions and Amendments (Box 295, Folder 6)
      - World Night-Focus on South Africa (Box 295, Folder 7)
    - Actions (Box 295, Folder 8)
    - Post-Convention materials (Box 295, Folder 9)
  - 32nd, 15-19 May 1991 (Atlanta, Georgia)
    - Interim 'Cycle I' Meetings, 1988-89 (Box 295, Folder 10-11)
    - Convention Preparation Meeting, 1 Feb 1989 (Box 295, Folder 12-13)
    - Mid-Triennium Conference, Mar 1990
      - Workshops (Box 295, Folder 14)
      - Survey (Box 295, Folder 15-17)
    - Resolutions Committee (Box 296, Folder 1-4)
    - Planning, 1989-91, n.d. (Box 296, Folder 5-7)
    - Convention Committee Meeting, 16-17 Feb 1990 (Box 296, Folder 8)
    - Convention Issues Task Group, Jan 1990 (Box 296, Folder 9)
    - Site Selection Committee, 1991 (Box 296, Folder 10)
    - Pre-convention materials
      - General (Box 296, Folder 11-12)
      - Who's Who and Action Agenda (Box 296, Folder 13)
    - Program and other convention materials
      - General (Box 297, Folder 1-2)
      - Amendments and Resolutions (Box 297, Folder 3)
      - Assemblies, Teen and Student (Box 297, Folder 4)
      - Recognition Dinner (Box 297, Folder 5)
      - Reports to (Box 297, Folder 6)
      - Workshops and Issue and Information Sessions (Box 297, Folder 7)
    - Actions and approved program priorities (Box 297, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 297, Folder 9)
    - Convention Take Home Kit (Box 297, Folder 10)
    - Post-convention materials (Box 297, Folder 11)
  - 33rd, 22-26 Jun 1994 (Los Angeles, California) "Preserve the Past, Create the Future"
    - Interim meetings
      - Cycle I Meetings, 1992 (Box 297, Folder 12)
      - Mid-Triennial Conference, 1993 (Box 297, Folder 13)
      - Convention Preparation Meetings, 1993-94 (Box 297, Folder 14-15)
    - Planning
      - General, 1991-94 (Box 298, Folder 1-3)
      - Finance (Box 298, Folder 4)
    - Resolutions Committee
      - General, 1993-94 (Box 298, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence (Box 298, Folder 6)
      - Amendments (Box 298, Folder 7)
      - Resolutions (Box 298, Folder 8)
    - Convention-mandated Task Forces (Box 298, Folder 9)
    - Pre-convention materials
      - General (Box 298, Folder 10)
      - Bulletins with enclosures (Box 298, Folder 11)
      - Action Agenda and Rules Book (Box 299, Folder 1)
      - Who's Who on the Ballot (Box 299, Folder 2)
    - Program and other convention materials
      - General (Box 299, Folder 3-4)
      - Program (Box 299, Folder 5)
      - Resolutions and Amendments for consideration (Box 299, Folder 6)
      - Workshops (Box 299, Folder 7)
      - Information Sections
        - General (Box 299, Folder 8)
        - Economic Security (Box 299, Folder 9)
        - Health and Health Care (Box 299, Folder 10)
        - Violence (Box 299, Folder 11)
      - Racial Justice Awards (Box 300, Folder 1)
      - Assemblies, Teen and Student (Box 300, Folder 2)
      - Grace Dodge Legacy Club and World Service Council luncheons (Box 300, Folder 3)
      - Reports to (Box 300, Folder 4)
    - Actions (Box 300, Folder 5)
    - Post Convention materials (Box 300, Folder 6)
  - 34th, 5-9 Jun 1996 (St. Louis, Missouri) "The Imperative is Now"
    - Pre-Convention
      - Planning, 1994-96 (Box 300, Folder 7-8)
      - Convention Committee (Box 300, Folder 9)
      - Resolutions Committee
        - General (Box 300, Folder 10-11)
        - Amendments (Box 300, Folder 12)
        - Resolutions (Box 300, Folder 13)
      - Site Selection Report, 1991 (Box 300, Folder 14)
      - Pre-Convention materials
        - General (Box 300, Folder 15)
    - Pre-Convention materials
      - Action Agenda I and II (Box 301, Folder 1)
      - Registration Materials and Program Information (Box 301, Folder 2)
      - Resolutions and Amendments (Box 301, Folder 3)
      - Rules Book and Who's Who (Box 301, Folder 4)
      - Study Guide (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - Convention materials
      - General (Box 301, Folder 6-7)
      - Program (Box 301, Folder 8)
      - Assemblies, Teen and Student (Box 301, Folder 9)
      - Salute to YWCA Volunteers and Staff in Public Office (Box 302, Folder 1)
      - Reports to
        - General (Box 302, Folder 2)
        - Strategic Planning Committee (Box 302, Folder 3)
    - Proceedings (Box 302, Folder 4)
    - Post-Convention Materials
      - General (Box 302, Folder 5)
      - Summary of Convention Action (Box 302, Folder 6)
  - 35th, 21-25 Jul 1998 (Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania)
    - Planning
      - General, 1996-98 (Box 302, Folder 7-9)
      - Site selection, 1995 (Box 302, Folder 10)
    - Pre-convention materials
      - General (Box 302, Folder 11)
      - Action Agenda and Rules Book (Box 303, Folder 1)
      - Resolutions and Amendments (Box 303, Folder 2)
      - Standards of Excellence and Who's Who (Box 303, Folder 3)
      - Mailing, Apr 1998 (Box 303, Folder 4)
    - Program and other convention materials
      - General (Box 303, Folder 5)
      - Reports to (Box 303, Folder 6)
      - Women Entrepreneur Awards (Box 303, Folder 7)
      - Convention binder (Box 303, Folder 8-9)
    - Post-Convention materials
      - General (Box 303, Folder 10)
      - Summary of Convention Action and Constitution and By-laws (Box 303, Folder 11)
      - News clippings (Box 303, Folder 12)
  - Special Convention, 14-16 Sep 2000 (Dallas, Texas) (Box 303, Folder 13)
  - 36th, 12-14 Jul 2001 (Albuquerque, New Mexico)
    - Planning
      - General (Box 303, Folder 14)
      - Corporate Sponsors
        - 1 of 2 (Box 303, Folder 15)
        - 2of 2 (Box 304, Folder 1)
    - Pre-convention Materials (Box 304, Folder 2)
    - Program and other convention materials
      - General (Box 304, Folder 3)
      - Association Credentials Report (Box 304, Folder 4)
      - Reorganization
        - "The Alternate Plan" (Box 304, Folder 5)
        - "Shared Vision" (Box 304, Folder 6)
        - "Steps To Absolute Change" (Box 304, Folder 7)
      - Reports to (Box 304, Folder 8)
      - Resolutions and Amendments (Box 304, Folder 9)